Zapewne zastanawiasz się,
czym jest Rails for Zombies?
Cóż, najprościej rzecz ujmując,
jest to interaktywny kurs
uczący podstaw tworzenia
aplikacji internetowych, przez
przeglądarke, używając Ruby on Rails.
Ale jest też dosadniejsza odpowiedź.
W świecie praktycznej nauki,
możemy korzystać z książek
jak i z screencast'ów, jednak
żaden z nich nie jest
interaktywny.
Dajcie spokoj! Przecież to
generacja Nintendo.
// do korekty
Dajcie mi cholernego joystick'a.
Oprócz tego występują
problemy z konfiguracją
Nieważne jak łatwo jest ustawić
Twój komputer do kodowania
rails['szyn'], ty prawdopodobnie
znajdziesz sposob jak to popsuć
czasem nawet nie z
Twojej winy.
Kiedy zapoznajesz sie z
czymś nowym, powinno to być
zabawą a nie sprawiać wrażenie,
że zostałeś wyrzucony
na głębokie wody.
By the time you get
to the water, you
// do korekty
should be booking it.
Ruby on Rails powinno być
pełne kucyków
i tęcz, prawda?
Dlatego powinnieneś(-aś) przynajmniej
mieć kolorową tęczę albo
być uzbrojonym w może pistolety
albo może nawet w shotgun'a/
O tak, szotgun'a.
But speaking of shotguns, you
have to be asking what does
// do korekty
this have to do with zombies?
Coż, to jest moment kiedy
prezentujemy naszą aplikacje.
Widzisz, Twitter jest zawsze dobrym
przykładem dla początkujących
Jak kolwiek, to jest oklepane,
więc  potrzebujemy
znaleźć coś nowego.
Ostatnio nauczyłem się o
spacerach zombie.
To wtedy gdy ludzie w dużych
miastach przebierają się za zombie
spotykajaca w określonym miejscu
i przemierzają ulice jako
nieumarli.
Właściwie dzieje się to w
całym kraju, i w Seatle
mieli ponad 4.000 zombie
przemierzających przez centrum.
// do korekty
Ale znowu, co to ma wspólnego
z Rails for Zombies?
Cóż, jeśli uczestniczych w
spacerach zombie i znajdziesz
przepyszny mózg, będziesz
potrzebować sposobu żeby
powiadomić znajomych zombie
o tym.
Zatem
is Twitter for Zombies.
Makes perfect sense, right?
So how does this zombie
thing work?
Well first, if you're not
familiar with the Ruby
language, head over to
tryruby.org and follow through
the Ruby tutorial there.
Then head back over to
Railsforzombies.org and click
the Start Course Now button
on the homepage.
You'll be taken to the first
video lesson for the course.
You can skip to a chapter
at the top if you
want to skip ahead.
And when you're done, just click
on the big green button
to start the challenges where
you'll have to do some coding
to get to level two.
In the challenge interface,
you'll see your total points,
the points you can earn from
this challenge, and the
challenge instructions.
To solve the challenge, you'll
need to write some code using
our in-browser code
editor here.
If you don't get it
right, you'll
see some error messages.
And if you're stuck, you can
take a look at some hints to
help keep pushing you forward.
Once you type in the correct
answer, you'll get a
congratulations screen where
you can continue on to the
next challenge or try
some extra credit.
The extra credit isn't verified,
it's just an
opportunity to practice
your rails coding.
Once you're ready to move on, on
the left side of the screen
you can jump around to
the other challenges.
Where you watch the video
lesson, learn the interface
shortcuts, or download
the video lesson
slides for later reference.
Once you finish Rails for
Zombies, you'll receive a
badge for your public profile,
unlock the final video.
And finally, you'll receive $5
in Code School cash that you
can use to enroll in Code School
and get access to Rails
for Zombies 2, Rails Testing for
Zombies, and Testing with
Rspec, along with all our other
courses and Code TV
screen casts.
Rails for Zombies is graciously
sponsored by New Relic.
Providing rails developers the
tools they need to monitor
their application performance.
Enough talk, it's time to learn
some Rails for Zombies.